BYEONGCHAN GWAK

1904-1803, 59, Deoksucheon 1-ro Deogyang-gu, Goyang-si, Korea Mobile: +82 10 3809 0973

Email: kbckbc@gmail.com

OVERVIEW

Deputy General Manager in the IT Service department with 15+ years of experience, with hopes of strengthening KSD's information security systems within public service in the future. Selected as a sponsorship trainee in recognition of my contribution to the development of Electronic securities issuance system (e-SAFE) and Electronic voting system (e-Vote), and automation of securities issuance. Skilled in enterprise architecture, programming methodologies, and industrial standards.

EDUCATION

POHANG UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (POSTECH)

Pohang, Korea

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

March 2000 – February 2008

- Scholarship student for the second semester of 2006
- Student representative of Computer Science Department in 2006

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KOREA SECURITIES DEPOSITORY (KSD)

Seoul, Korea

A special public entity and the only Central Securities Depository (CSD) in Korea. Manage and supervise a wide range of securities-related business activities, including issues, deposits, clearance, settlement, and entitlement processing.

Deputy General Manager, IT Service Department

September 2019 – Present

- Maintaining KSD's several systems, which generates annual fee revenue of USD 200 Mil.
 - Maintenance of e-SAFE(Electronic Securities Issuance), e-Vote(Electronic Voting System), CrowdNet(Public Funding Service)

Deputy General Manager, e-Securities Development TF

November 2016 – September 2019

- Participated in establishing e-Securities system (budget: USD 50 Mil. member: 40 KSD employees and 166 external personnel); contributed to improving efficiency and security by digitalizing all securities related works
 - Participate as a selected employee out of a total of 500 employees
 - Led over 20 developers as a leader of the securities issuing team
 - Analyzed, designed, developed, and led testing of application programs
 - Created basic data by digitalizing overall securities according to the related regulations
 - saved USD 13 Mil. from overall fee in 2019

Manager, e-Vote Development TF

March 2014 - November 2016

- Developing a Web Voting System for shareholders
 - Korea's first and only general shareholders' voting system
 - More than 75,000 individual shareholders participated in voting in 2020

Assistant Manager

November 2007 - March 2014

- Responsible for the operation and distribution of SAFE, a new securities issuance system
 - Over 7 years of maintenance on the securities issuing system
 - Developed batch program call services to automate repetitive manual tasks
 - Developed several systems to manage corporate rights schedules

NAMO INTERACTIVE Seoul, Korea

IT Company; provides #1 Web page editor in Korea, Mobile game provider

Software Developer

November 2004 – January 2006

- Mobile phone game development and release
 - Converted existing game sources (C++, Java) into WIPI platform to release games to carriers like STK, KT, LG
 - Supplied several self-developed mobile games to carriers

DONGBANG LIGHTECH

Seoul, Korea

IT Company; provides Automatic Chinese character recognition solution

Software Developer

January 2004 – November 2004

- Maintenance of high-speed processing system for automatic recognition of old document images
 - Improved the system so that Chinese characters that the computer cannot clearly recognize can be entered separately

JUNGWOO SYSTEM Seoul, Korea

IT Company; provides system integration

Assistant Software Developer

September 2002 – December 2003

- KEPCO(Korea Electric Power Corporation) system maintenance
 - TIMS, KEPCO's subscriber management system, system maintenance
 - TGIS, KEPCO's CAD management system, system maintenance

LANGUAGES AND SKILLS

- Languages: Korean (Native), English (Fluent)
- Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, Python, PHP, SQL
- Technology: Data Modeling, Enterprise Application Design, Struts Framework, Object-Oriented Programming, Event-Driven Architecture, Service-Oriented Architecture, AJAX
- Environments: Windows, Linux (RedHat, Ubuntu), Unix (Solaris, AIX, FreeBSD), Cygwin, Oracle, MS SQL, MySQL, WebLogic, .NET Framework

MISCELLANEOUS

- Selected for Full-Time IT Master's Degree Sponsorship (only one out of 650 eligible employees) (2020)
- Awarded the Best Practice Award by the President of KSD (2016)
- Participated in rock band Club STEELER as a bassist and experienced numerous stage performances